birthdayinabox.com 2011-06-30

# Privacy Policy at Birthday in a Box

Privacy Policy   

> What Type of Information Do We Collect?  
>  How Do We Collect Your Information?  
>  How Do We Use Your Information?  
>  Links to Other Websites  
>  Third-Party Advertising Companies  
>  Security Information  
>  Changes to Our Privacy Policy  
>  Contacting Birthday in a Box

Birthday in a Box takes your online privacy seriously, and we respect the importance of ensuring the privacy of our customers, our registered users, and information that they may provide about their children. Therefore, we have created this Privacy Policy to instruct you about: 

  * The type of information we collect from you when you visit our site, purchase our products, register for or respond to emails, or otherwise contact us;
  * How and why we gather information from or about you;
  * How we may use the information we gather; and,
  * The options available to you regarding your personal information.

You must be 18 years or older to use the Birthday in a Box Web Site, become a customer, subscribe to our mailing list, and/or become a registered user.

References in this Privacy Policy to our "Company", "we", or "us" include Birthday in a Box, its direct and indirect subsidiaries and their affiliates.

WHAT TYPE OF INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT

Birthday in a Box collects information in order to create a positive shopping experience, communicate with you, properly process orders, and ensure excellent customer service. We may also provide you with valuable information, promotional offers, or discounts from selected third parties and us.

We typically gather several types of information: 

  * Personally identifiable information ("PII") that is used to identify, contact, or locate a person. This includes information such as your name, address, telephone number, email address, credit card information, and, if you choose to provide us with that information, your child’s gender and date of birth. 
  * Non-personally identifiable information ("Non-PII"), which is also referred to as aggregate and anonymous data. This information is not linked to a particular person. It is used to gather information such as statistics, traffic and demographic information, browser types, and marketing data. 
  * PII or Non-PII about you from third parties. This may include information such as demographic or geographic data that was provided to a marketing partner in conjunction with a promotion or campaign. We may combine this information with information we have already collected in order to personalize your shopping experience with us or to communicate with you.

HOW DO WE COLLECT YOUR INFORMATION

We may gather information through our Web Site, emails, customer surveys, telephone, mail, fax, and third parties. Specific information about some of the collection methods is described below.

Providing us with PII is your choice, and you can always choose not to do so, but not doing so may prevent us from being able to process your order. We will not sell, share, or lease your PII for any purpose except as set forth in this Privacy Policy. 

You can request that we change, update, or delete the personal information you provide by contacting us at [customerservice@birthdayinabox.com](mailto:customerservice@birthdayinabox.com) or by telephone at 800-989-5506 or 301-956-1616. Please note that it may take up to a week to process your change request.

**Account Registration and Checkout**

At checkout, we offer you the opportunity to create a Birthday in a Box customer account. Your e-mail address together with a password is used to secure your profile and to speed any future purchases. Your access to the private information we store requires use of your password. We recommend that you do not share your password with anyone.

During checkout, you may also choose to provide us with your child’s name, gender, and birth date. This information is optional and is not required to make a purchase. It is used to assist us in providing you with personalized promotional birthday reminders, updated party theme information, and valuable party planning content.

**E-Mail Promotions and Newsletters**

When you create a Birthday in a Box customer account or purchase a product from our site, you automatically opt into our mailing list unless you elect to opt out of such mailings. The option to opt out is provided during the checkout process, and in each promotional mailing.

We use our mailing list to provide you, via email, with information about our Company, provide promotional offers and party planning information prior to your child’s next birthday, and deliver other special offers, discounts and promotions from our Company and select third party partners. If we provide an offer from a third party partner, we do not provide that partner your PII.

All emails contain simple instructions on how to unsubscribe. You may also elect not to receive these offers through our Web Site or by emailing [unsubscribe@birthdayinabox.com](mailto:unsubscribe@birthdayinabox.com). If using the email option, please allow 5 business days for us to process your request.

**IP Address**

Your IP address is a number that is assigned by your ISP (Internet Service Provider) to your computer to identify its location. We may use your IP address to identify your geographic demographic, help diagnose an Internet problem, administer our website, and provide relevant content.

**Cookies**

A "Cookie" is a small bit of data sent to your browser from a Web server, delivered through a Web browser, and stored on your computer.

It is used to let us know that you are a returning customer or visitor and allow you to select items to purchase, and it may be used to provide you with a personalized user experience. 

Most Web browsers allow you to limit the use of cookies on your computer, generally in the privacy or security section. However, many companies, including Birthday in a Box, use cookies to keep track of your items as you add to the shopping cart. Turning off your cookies may prevent you from placing an order.

**Web Beacons (also known as Web Bugs, Tracking Pixels or Clear Gifs)**

A Web beacon consists of a small string of software code that allows anonymous tracking of NON-PII of visitors, customers, and other Web Site usage as well as Non-PII information on purchases and other click information. Web beacons may be used for many purposes including gathering of site statistics, visitor demographics, advertising reporting, and to personalize a user experience.

HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

Birthday in a Box collects information in order to create a positive shopping experience, communicate with you, properly process orders, and ensure excellent customer service. We may also provide you with valuable information, promotional offers, or discounts from selected third parties and us.

We share the information collected through our site with our direct and indirect subsidiaries and their affiliates and the Web sites they operate.

Our Company may share Non-PII, such as aggregate user statistics, demographic information, and web site usage information with third parties.

Our Company employs third parties to perform functions on our behalf, such as hosting, sending email and/or other communications, data analysis, marketing assistance, credit card payment processing and customer services. It may be necessary for our Company to share PII with such third parties for use for such purposes.

Except as provided below, we do not share your PII with non-affiliated third parties without your permission. Certain emails that you receive from Birthday in a Box, as well as other Company sites, contain links to other Web sites. Birthday in a Box is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other Web sites. 

Additionally, we may also disclose PII you provide via this site in connection with the sale, assignment, or other transfer of the business or a portion of the business of our site, including a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, sale of assets or other corporate change; or to respond to law enforcement requests; or where required by applicable laws, court orders, or government regulations; or to protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our site; or to protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public (among other things, this means that if you provide false information or attempt to pose as someone else, information about you may be disclosed as part of any investigation into your actions).

LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES

We may offer links on Birthday in a Box to partner, sponsor and/or advertiser Web sites. Links to advertisers typically appear on the confirmation page that is triggered after you complete an order.

If you click on those links and choose to participate in services and tools offered on our partner, sponsor and/or advertiser Web sites, you may be required to provide PII to these advertisers and partners. Each advertiser and partner may request different information from you, and you are subject to the privacy policies and terms of use of the third party, not ours. If you have additional questions about how one of these third parties uses information about you, we urge you to contact them directly.

As stated above, our Company is not responsible for the privacy policies of third parties and cannot control the practices of these third parties.

THIRD-PARTY ADVERTISING COMPANIES

If you purchase a product from Birthday in a Box, the order confirmation page will often contain an advertisement. Many of these advertisements are not selected and delivered by us, but by network advertising companies that manage and provide advertising for Company Web sites. These companies utilize certain technologies to deliver advertisements and marketing messages. They may also collect and use Non-PII about your visits to our Web sites and other Web sites in order to present advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice or to opt out of having this information used by third-party ad servers to provide targeted ads, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp>.

**Third Party Cookies and Other Tracking Technology**

In the course of serving advertisements on the order confirmation page that appears after you purchase products on our Web site, our third-party advertisers may place or recognize a unique "cookie" on your browser. Company third party advertisers may use other tracking technology, including without limitation, Web beacons to recognize you and provide better managed advertising on our Web sites. Third party cookies and web beacons are governed by the third party’s specific privacy policy, not our privacy policy. 

SECURITY OF INFORMATION

Birthday in a Box has numerous security measures in place to protect you from the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control including the use of third party security monitoring services.

When you place an order on our Web Site, we use secure socket layer (SSL) encryption technology to ensure that your data is passed in a secure manner. Additionally, your credit card information is stored in an encrypted format. Although we take every reasonable precaution to ensure that your personal information is safeguarded and stored in a secure manner, we cannot guarantee the security of the information we receive.

Sections of our Web site may require a password to access information. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your password and, therefore, we recommend that you do not share it.

CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

We may amend our privacy policy at any time. If we amend this privacy policy to permit material changes in the way we collect, use and/or share your PII, we will notify you of such amendment by placing a notice on our sites covered by this privacy policy.

CONTACTING BIRTHDAY IN A BOX

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or the practices of this site you can contact us at:

Birthday in a Box   
7951 Cessna Avenue  
Gaithersburg, Maryland 20879

Telephone: 1-800-989-5506/301-956-1616

To contact Birthday in a Box by e-mail, please [click here](mailto:customerservice@birthdayinabox.com).

© 2008, 2009, 2010 Birthday in a Box. All rights reserved.

Last updated March 22, 2010.
